Charles Deiss Media Materials 1928-1947 PC004
Test - Paleontology Collection
Charles Deiss Media Materials
1928-1947
Test - Paleontology Collection
Deiss, Charles F. (Charles Frederick), 1903-1959
PC004
5 card catalog drawers
Charles Deiss was the chair of the Department of Geological Sciences and the Indiana State Geologist. Deiss is well-known for his work on Cambrian faunas and stratigraphy from western North America.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research. Advance notice required.
Biographical Note
Charles Deiss was a paleontologist and geologist who was born in Kentucky and studied at Miami University of Ohio (BA, 1925). In 1946 he moved to Bloomington, Indiana to become chair of the Department of Geological Sciences and the Indiana State Geologist. Deiss was instrumental in establishing the IU Field Station near Whitehall Montana and he collected many fossils from the Paleozoic sections in that region. He is especially known for his work on Cambrian faunas and stratigraphy from western North America.
Arrangement
The collection was arranged according to author's organization.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains of film sheet negatives, prints, mounted photographs, and slides related to his field of study, special interest and people.
Acquisition Information
Inherited from the author.
Geology, Stratigraphic–Cambrian; Geology, Stratigraphy–Ordovician; Geology–Montana; Deiss, Charles F. (Charles Frederick), 1903-1959
- Media Materials, 1928-1947
  - Located in Drawer14 - 94 Geology slides, 87 negatives and prints, 1930-1947 (Box 1)
    - Technical negatives of formations (Box 1)
    - Special interest and people (Box 1)
  - Located in Drawer11 - 780 Mounted photographs, 25 prints, catalog cards, 1928-1935 (Box 2)
    - Locality prints, mounted photographs (Box 2)
    - Locality cards (Box 2)
  - Located in Drawer12 - 1,090 Mounted photographs, catalog cards, 1936-1941 (Box 3)
    - Locality prints (Box 3)
  - Located in Drawer13 - 430 Photo prints, catalog cards, 1936-1941 (Box 4)
    - Charles Deiss on muletrain in Montana (Box 4)
    - Locality prints (Box 4)
    - Locality cards (Box 4)